Hello, I'm your host David Barnard, and
with me today RevenueCat CEO Jacob
Eiding. Our guest today is Bruno Virlet,
co-founder of The Grizzly Labs, makers
of Genius Scan, one of the oldest and
best scanning apps for smartphones. On
the podcast, we talk with Bruno about
putting customers ahead of metrics,
why there's still massive opportunity to
build successful apps, and how a server
crash turned into an accidentally
successful AB test.
Hey Bruno, thanks very much for joining
us on the podcast today.
Hey David, thanks for having me.
And Jacob, really nice chatting with you
today as well.
Always, David, always. But I'm very
excited to talk to Bruno because you
were one of, I think, the 15 people who
signed up for RevenueCat in 2017. Like,
when we launched in December, you poked
around. We never made it happen for a
while, but like you were very very very
very very early, and somehow we've never
talked directly before. But I always
joke that the I think about probably a
lot of people like this, but I I have
always the first 20 sign-ups for
RevenueCat burned in my head because I
looked at them in the database so many
times. So, I'm very excited to get the
backstory today, so.
Yeah, you got some convincing, but you
finally got me, so.
Yeah, you know, 5 years later, well, no,
more than that, 7 years later.
Well, speaking of long time in the
making, Genius Scan and your company has
been a many year journey, almost 15
years in the making. So, I did want to
kind of go back to the founding because
I think a lot of people would be
interested to hear that whole story of
of how you got started, how you got that
early product market fit, and then how
you grew that to what today is a really
incredible business. You have 5 million
MAU, 10% team, like that's a fantastic
success story for a bootstrapped app.
But yeah, tell us the story.
Yeah, so Genius Scan
is the main app that we develop as a
mobile app development studio, and we
started it like 15 years almost 15 years
ago. It will be 15 years in June.
Actually, we didn't want to I mean, we
didn't plan to start Genius Scan. So, it
was my co-founder and myself, we were uh
students at the University of Illinois.
And we were roommates. iPhone was quite
new at that time. I mean, well, I guess
that iPhone was 2007. Yeah, well, I
think it's 2007 the iPhone, but then the
App Store just opened publicly to
third-party apps in 2009, right? I think
at the
2008 8
2008? Okay. Yeah, so in 2009, basically,
I mean, I was like, "Uh maybe we should
make an app. It would be fun." I was
more like in the Linux development
before, but my co-founder was in my
roommate, I guess, at the time
was in doing a image processing
research. And so, we said, "What could
we do with that?" We brainstormed, and
we had this great idea. It was to make
an app to scan paintings in museums.
You would do go to the Louvre in France.
You would scan a painting. I mean, take
take a photo of a painting, and
and you would get all the information
about it, like who who painted it.
Okay, so it was like augmented almost
augmented reality, like
Yeah, it was augmented reality
like, you know, years before it it was
something.
So, we started working on that. After a
while, I mean, we had it kind of
working, but then we had two problems.
One was that we used a technology which
was called SIFT. It was like basically
features that you embed in an image and
key points that you can identify
to recognize an image under any angle.
I mean, yeah, it was a
And the problem the problem with this
technology is that there were some
patents on it.
And you at the time we were just
students in a dorm room, I guess, and we
were like, "Patents? We're going to be
sued by Americans. You know, what?"
So, this was in late 2000, so like 2008
and 9. So, this was before like kind of
the modern AI revolution and all the
stuff. So, this This have been like They
wouldn't even called it machine learning
at the time. They would have called it
like vision
Yeah, it was computer vision. But yeah,
and actually my main roommate was doing
computer vision at the university. So
yeah.
The kids don't have any idea how good
they have it these days. They slap a
image recognition in like with one API
call.
Throw more transformers at it. It'll
figure it out eventually, you know. But
yeah, CV was like a different ball game.
So the patent scared you and so you
Okay, yeah. I mean we were I mean we
There were there were alternatives.
There were like you know open source
alternatives. And then also there was
another problem that at that time like
if you imagine someone going to the
Louvre in Paris to scan pictures, you
probably was a tourist, you know, coming
from China or the US. And at that time
there were no like cellular I mean when
you went abroad like roaming fees were
crazy high. So
When I went to Europe in 2010, I had no
cell phone for 3 weeks, right? Like I
went to internet cafes.
Exactly. So so you would have to
download the database in advance on your
phone. It was like huge because it was a
database of images to I mean even the
because we only had signatures of the of
the image. So it would it would be huge.
It would take I mean
and so we all said like I mean who's
going to do that? Like
but the thing is that when preparing
this app, so the way Guillaume was doing
it was like taking photos of
Van Gogh painting on his desk all the
time. And actually we I mean we we were
detecting the the painting on his desk
and we were like
Okay, we could detect any kind of
document like that. And that's how we we
said okay, maybe we will will start
doing a
document scanning app and we'll go back
to the paintings later.
And so you know, 15 years later
we are still on the document scanning.
And and that's how it started. And for
the funny story is that I was
I mean what triggered actually the start
of the development was in I think it's
May 2009. So we had basically the tech
but it was in developed in MATLAB on the
computer. It was not like a mobile app.
And uh
in 2000 in May 2009 I was going back to
France for a wedding and actually I got
stuck in the Chicago O'Hare Airport
because of the Icelandic volcano. You
remember like the I don't remember the
name. It's like
I used to flew. And so I was actually I
I had flown to Chicago and and and I got
my ticket refunded by
by the airline. I don't know how but
it happened. I was like I saved the
money of the trip to Paris and so I went
to the
Apple Store in Chicago, purchased a
MacBook because I didn't have one at the
time and went back to Champaign,
Illinois and that's where I started so I
started developing the app. And actually
it's what's
reached strike me
is that that was in May and in June 22
2010 the app was launched on the App
Store. So you know basically the first
version of the app was a a month of a
month and a half maybe of development
and it picked up really quickly. So I
don't have the exact numbers in in in
mind but it was like
we put it as a free app on the App Store
and it just shot up the rankings.
Was it the first or one of the early
scanning apps?
I mean there was one another one is what
Yeah, I think it was the first app. I
mean
like the first
that was working quite well.
Yeah, this was like one of the
non-obvious like
life-changing I don't know important
utilities that a great camera and a good
phone could do cuz I never it never
crossed my mind that like oh I don't
need a scanner anymore. Like I can I can
get a good scan good enough scan just
with an app that that knows what it's
doing and a camera.
And so yeah, I can imagine being one of
the first and like just locking that
down.
Yeah, it was kind of magic because for
for users I think it was it worked
pretty well because you it was like one
of those first apps that kind of bridged
the physical world and the
digital world. It's like it's almost
like
AR, right? You take a a document and
then you we would warp it and present it
to you very clean. So it was a I I think
it was fun to use and uh and the plan
was to put it free as a free app for a
few days because it was a you know, it
was like a launch offer. So, we would do
that and then after a few days we would
just put it paid and then you know, make
some money. And so, after a few days I
put it as a paid app and immediately we
went from like I don't know, thousands
of downloads a day to one to downloads a
day. I think it was 99 cents to be to be
Wow. Wow, that just shows this is 2010.
So, this is like I think people forget
how much the basement there was of apps
in the early days of the App Store. Like
there was a free fall from like being
able to make money like selling an app
for you know, $10 or $20 on the desktop
to a race to the bottom happened very
very quickly.
Mhm. Yeah, that's why it was a race to
the bottom, exactly.
So, so basically we panicked and we put
it back as a free app. We were like we
were worried etc. I mean, we were just
students. We know we didn't have to make
a living out of that.
Yeah, I mean, a few thousand free users
is better than $2 a day. You know what I
mean? Like
After that we we were lucky to be
featured by Apple in the months after
that. I think that was the summer. I may
remember incorrectly but where iAds
launched to the you know, supposedly
super high quality ads from Apple and
they had like at the time they had like
a crazy high eCPMs. I think you had a
like $10 eCPM so
I know, like $30 I launched with iAd
where they just Apple just spending just
paying developers basically.
no, they set it up with brands. So, like
massive brands like Disney and I worked
on the dang SDK.
You were inside Apple?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, when iAds was coming
out. Yeah, yeah, yeah, I was. Yeah.
Yeah, it was and it was really well. So,
we were like, okay, that's you know,
interesting. We start we are starting to
to make some money with app even though
it wasn't like really the plan at the
time. So, we kept it free and I think in
December 2009, so we we We a paid
version of the app. So, there was a free
version, and there was a paid up front
version. The next year, I I think that
in-app purchases were introduced. So,
then we had in-app purchases in the So,
as a lifetime, you know.
That was basically to remove the ads.
Yeah.
And that was to remove the ads, and and
slowly we introduced like advanced
features. If you want to export to
Dropbox quickly, so this was called
Genius Scan Plus. That was a premium
plan, right?
That would have been fairly early, like
back in I mean, I guess if you were
doing not as a subscription, but as a as
a one-time in-app purchase.
I think it was as soon as I mean,
we basically Apple announced it, and
then we announced in-app purchases
availability, and we, you know, we
benefited from that.
Yeah, I wish I could go back in time and
and do a better freemium strategy for
some of my old apps. I mean, people
don't even realize how good we have it
these days with subscriptions and
everything else, cuz my apps, I had a
free version. So, my like one of my
early apps was Gas Cubby. It tracks fuel
economy and vehicle maintenance. It was
actually quite successful. I sold it and
did really well from it, but I had Gas
Cubby Light that was a free version that
had limited features. And then when you
hit the limit, you got pushed to the
paid upfront app. And so, I mean, man,
back then it was just such like there
were no kind of free trials and like the
multiple SKUs, and uh early days of the
App Store. It's crazy how much better
things have actually gotten on the
monetization front, but I mean, happy
accident, honestly, because if you would
have been paid upfront,
we wouldn't be here today. I think,
yeah.
What was the story for you and your
co-founder from it becoming this like
side project sort of like curiosity to
like, "Hey, this is this is something
worth working on." Like when did you
make enough money that you could like
not have to worry about a job?
We we didn't want to be entrepreneurs.
Like I mean, originally, it's like we
we wanted to make an app. And it is
Well, we were not predicting to be
entrepreneurs, basically. So, what when
we did this app in 2010 and and then
then we graduated in the summer. So,
Guillaume, my co-founder, went back to
France
and he started working for a a company
in France and I I stayed in the US and I
went to Seattle. I started working at
Amazon.
And then we kept working on it at nights
and weekends and
it kind of picked up. I mean, it kept
growing, you know, slowly, but it kept
growing without work. I think we did I
don't think I even remember when, but we
started the Android version of the app.
And after a while, then I I moved back
to San Francisco actually for to work
for a YC company. And funny story also
that they contacted me because they
found the scanning app and they had
scanning needs. So, it was called a
1000 memories and they were doing like a
scanning of old old photos, family
photos. And I kept working on the side,
you know, on Genius Scan. So, after
after a while, we were like, "Okay, we
we work for our day job, but we also
work on that. We really like I mean, it
means that we really like that. We
should go full-time." And at that Well,
in 2014, we went full-time on it. We had
you know, enough money to make a to to
make a living out of it.
So, it was already making enough money
that you didn't have to like starve.
Yeah, that's I mean, we can talk about
that later, but basically to we didn't
have to raise funds, right? We
Just do it. Yeah. I think also too, did
did you find that once you had made the
jump and like once this was your main
thing, did you find it I mean, obviously
you had more time to work on it, but I
also feel like if it's your only source
of income, you're a little more like
aggressive and motivated to like make it
work better and like grow it and things
like that. If if it's all you've got.
So, I think when we started, we had like
some conf- I mean, we we could live out
of it. So, we were not like
grinding to make a living. So, I think
if we were like if it was just enough to
live, maybe we would have what you
describe is is true in our case. Yes, I
mean, we it's we were full-time on it.
We had the time to maybe explore some
things that we couldn't have otherwise
and then grow a team, something we
didn't want at the beginning, but
You know, for those listening and and
kind of maybe tuning out at this point
thinking, "Ah, I don't have a time
machine to go back to 2009 and build a
scanning app." I actually think today
we're kind of seeing this new wave with
like AI, AR is coming. Like what was
unique at What's so interesting about
this story is that there was a
combination of multiple technologies
that came along that you leveraged into
a business and it grew over time. So,
today there's all sorts of new stuff
coming out with AR with new sensors,
with new And so like there's been so
many different points along the history
of apps that new things have come out
that create new opportunities to create
new businesses. And sometimes it does
take years and years and years to grow.
You know, indies out there listening
when, you know, it's like 3 years in and
you haven't made that much progress, but
then the fourth year it's like, "Wow, I
can actually go full-time." Like it
happens and I think it can still happen
today.
Yeah, and even at the time everyone was
saying the gold rush was over. So, maybe
it's not the gold rush of the early App
Store days, but you know, I mean I think
like subscriptions came for instance and
they they started a new like dimension
for monetization themselves. So, so it's
always like you can always say it's too
late, but maybe it's too late to do, you
know, what was
I mean, the thing is is by the time you
recognize people being successful, those
people it wasn't obvious when they did
it, right?
Yeah, we don't go compete with
Microsoft, right?
Right, exactly. Like people that you're
looking at folks who are like like
struggling to start right now and you're
looking at folks that are already
successful and you're like, "Oh, I
missed the boat." It's like, "Well, you
missed that boat, right?" There's always
another boat. At least there has been
for 1,500 years. Like we've been always
like inventing another boat you can
catch. And but the the root story of
like recognizing an unfilled
technological niche, building something.
You guys took a like, you know, one path
which was like slow burn, build it on
the side, eventually have enough like
that that there's many different
versions of that you can do, but it all
starts with like finding something that
people don't have that they want, right?
Yeah, and I mean and you are giving us
credit for that, right? Because to be
honest, we started like it was like a
serendipity, right? When we started this
scanning up, we had the needs because we
were in a students in the US, we always
like we are moving around, we didn't
have much stuff, so we would scan
documents. We had to register for, you
know, immigration stuff. So we are
always always had documents to scan, so
we kind of had a need, but like everyone
Yeah, I think also you you must factor
in like a like the luck factor to be
sometimes the right place at the right
time and yeah.
No, but the luck factor but that's you
name the company after yourself,
clearly.
It was ironic, right?
Yeah, the luck factor is that you got
right the first time. Like that's the
luck. You know what I mean? Like I think
if Well, actually you kind of didn't. It
was the second time. It was the second
time because the Mona Lisa scanning app
never went anywhere, right?
I like the whole idea of the catching
the boat kind of thing. I mean, we see
this in RevenueCat data. We should do
this, Jacob. Do an analysis of apps
founded in different like different
launch dates of apps. And I bet every
single year we could find an indie, a
big company, a mid-size company, a
bootstrap company, a funded company like
in 2015,
there's a cohort that launched and some
became huge and some are indie success
stories. In 2016, it's like there's
boats leaving the harbor every
Yeah, we have we have now seven years of
cohorts and with the exception of maybe
the first year when they were very thin
cohorts of very few people, like every
cohort has somebody in it still alive,
still thriving, still growing, still
compounding. So that's the luck aspect
of it. Like it might not always be you
in that cohort, right? But like it'll be
somebody, right? There's a boat to
catch, you know?
Yeah, and also I think when you find
what this idea is like if people will
jump on the boat, then you will find you
know, after this boat you will find a
lot of, you know, other boats trying to
Other boats.
to copy what, you know, to do the same
like take the same wind and and and you
know, like for instance there are like
now there are many scanning apps and
many of them are like I think doing
well. I don't know how profitable they
are and that
they've been around for a while. So, I
think every idea then you can like
replicate it to some extent and after a
while maybe the market is saturated and
and then you need to catch another, you
know,
Yeah, it gets harder. But like I mean
that's a good that's a good point to
talk about cuz what when did Apple like
iOS has native scanning now, right?
Yeah, you not only have a ton of
competitors and it's a another kind of
fun part of the story. You not only have
like hundreds of scanning apps in the
App Store now. It's been like one of the
more popular categories for people to go
try and build an app. But not only that,
then Apple introduced scanning native
and now you have AI and like it like
seems so obvious. Like how do you think
about competing and how have you thought
about competing in this landscape where
it's just like a thousand flowers are
blooming but you're one of those.
I mean we we worried about about it a
lot early. I think when the new scanning
apps were launching or competitors were
launching new features in the early
years we were like oh no, we are done.
What are we going to do, you know? And
even worse like with yeah, I think WWDC
after like first it was fun and after a
while you had like every every year you
had like this uneasy feeling of what are
they going to announce that might, you
know, affect us in a bad way. And
scanning like when they released like
scanning so they released the your
scanning in notes in the files app I
think. We were like okay, maybe I mean
how good is that for us and
you know, what everyone says that I mean
Apple covers like the basic needs and
when you want to go deeper you will find
a more specialized app. They will also,
you know, make people aware that oh, you
can do scanning with your device. So,
has it affected us in a bad way? Like we
never saw, you know, Apple release
scanning and our growth stalls
or we lose customers. I mean, we have
like anecdotes, you know, some people
telling us, "Oh,
I stopped using your app because Oh, why
would I use your app? Because I use
scanning in notes, but I think in
practice we are fairly confident now
that our scanning is is better."
I'm biased, but but it It has I mean, it
like the quality of the scanning is you
know, speed of it is actually better.
And we offer also like a bunch of
features. It's not only scanning, it's
like
you know, scanning, organizing your
documents, exporting them. People are
really like
surprising how I mean, important it is
that's two parts, you know, for for
people.
Make it easy to export. For instance, we
have features like where you scan a
document and it will auto export it to a
specific folder in Dropbox depending on
the document name.
I imagine there's a lot of like
prosumers that use
Exactly, yeah. Yeah, and could be like
small you know, small companies. They
need like they want something a bit more
advanced. They they
want something that scans well for
instance, in low light conditions, which
other
do maybe as well. And a lot of small
factors that when people do some
research, they will still like
go to
people like us. So now we are more like
I mean, we are less worried about
competition. And we have like you know,
we have because we have the competition
from other independent like companies.
We have competition from the platform.
So Apple and Google have
introduced like scanning, but also
every major like cloud storage, so
Google Drive, Dropbox, Box, they all
have a scanning module in the in the
app. I mean, we are still growing. So
maybe we will grow more if they didn't
exist, maybe.
Yeah, two observations is one, in this
category, there's a lot of charlatans.
All right, as David was kind of alluding
to, there's a lot of people who just
make the cheapest, fastest, whatever,
pump it with ads, do cross promo. It's
actually a piece of junk. So I think you
all being like one of the few reputable
brands, it's probably you and Adobe, you
know what I mean, who actually are like
kind of a trustworthy brand in this.
That's probably a huge advantage that
nobody can replicate. You can't
replicate that earnestness, right? And
that reality. So, you're somewhat
differentiated, even if not by features
even, but just by brand. But then also,
I think and this kind of goes back to
the bootstrap point that you guys are
bootstrap, that you haven't taken
capital. I think like it depends on your
expectations for return on investment,
too, right? And that's up to you. If you
and your co-founder are the sole owners
and you guys can kind of decide like
what your expectations are, you can
survive well in a in a very competitive
environment. Most businesses in the
world are in extremely competitive
environments, and there's still great,
you know, ways to spend your time and
build things.
It's when you need to win a
winner-takes-all market that competition
becomes a problem, right?
Yeah, it's it's like
like food delivery apps, you know? Like
in Europe, I don't know how it is in the
US, but they've been like you know,
killing each other like and buying each
other. Some have a bankrupt, and and
it's super competitive because they they
you know, they raised huge funds, and
they need to basically they need to take
over the market. And now there are like
a few in in France you have Deliveroo,
Uber Eats, and that's it. Yeah, it has
to be a monopoly given how much money
has been pumped in it, right? Otherwise,
it's not worth the the return on
investment. And in our case, we yeah, we
see that very differently. We want to
you know, we want to be profitable, but
we I mean, we invested time in it,
right? We exchanged
time for money at the beginning, but
otherwise, we don't need we I mean, we
don't have a need for ROI. And
currently, you know, both me and my
co-founder, we have kids. We want to
spend time with them. That's we have the
freedom of doing that and to like really
spend time with them, and we would
have raised, you know,
money or we would be super aggressive in
our you know, monetization. Maybe we
wouldn't be able to
You might end up like one of those
charlatans I mentioned, right?
Exactly. And it's it's it's important to
know why why you are in business I mean,
what are you in business for, right? And
I know your your motto is like help
developer make more money, but it's also
like
you know, help like
Only as much as you want to make, you
know, and not a dollar more.
Exactly. I mean, it's
it's it helps you live the life you want
like in a way, all right?
Yeah, really you have to think about
what's success for you. And it maybe
it's not just the most profitable. And
about that as well, like I've been
worried about like
I mean, we have we have tried I've tried
to improve like ASO on the App Store and
we are fairly I mean, well ranked. So,
if you look for scanning, we'll find us
in the five results. And I've looked at
the you know, the one above us and I'm
like, why are they above us? And I have
tried
to understand all the reasons why they
could be on top of us and and I mean,
there's no like reason, I think, due to
our the way we named the app or
we have like a very good number of
ratings per downloads, everything that
figures, you know, recommend you do
well. And and there is one thing is like
the download velocity. I think it that's
important. Like the more downloads you
have, the more you raise in the rankings
in the search results. But, you know,
it's kind of the I don't know do you say
in in French we say snake eating its own
tail, but um
Chicken and egg
Chicken and egg Yeah, the chicken and
egg problem. And and because if we're
not in the top results, then And I
looked at the top ones, but then if you
look at them, you see that most of them
they purchase App Store ads. So,
in the end, they are before us in the
rankings, they are purchasing ads, but
what's what's their profitability? When
you see their revenue numbers in App
Figures, that doesn't deduct how much
they pay for ads.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. They're probably
they're probably running incredibly thin
margins, maybe even negative margins
because they're leveraged. They might be
borrowing money.
Maybe. I don't know. Maybe not, but I'm
I'm sure they are not as profitable as
they look on the on the App Figures
revenue numbers.
And so,
again, yeah, yeah, we have to to look at
it's hard to you have to to know exactly
where you are and if you are maybe not
at the top one, maybe you are doing well
enough. Yeah.
You have more equity in your app than
somebody else, right? That may be above
you in the rankings in the fact that,
you know, it actually is profitable and
it or more profitable and that that
increases the like value. And then
there's I think this is this is gets for
a bit philosophical, but you know, we
tend to talk about equity and an an
asset in terms of the dollars it would
get at market. But then you were
alluding to there's more than just the
dollars that we get at market is as to
the value it is to you and your
co-founder and your team. It's like it's
meaningful work. It's something to do.
It's like a way to live. It's it's all
of these things.
And even though like the independence we
have like we because we we've been
approached a few times like by companies
interested in and you know, the first
you start talking with them, but after a
few times like you say just no. I mean
we we like what we are doing if you
know, if we were
acquired we would you know, work two
years for you and then what would we do?
We would like this app is I mean super
interesting to work on it. We have
customers who love the app. When we add
a new feature we can see the effect like
we have customers thanking us for for
for it. It's like super rewarding.
You're starting to make it sound like
you don't like money and that the app is
just like this stagnant annuity that
sits off in the other
I said it's growing David. It's not
stagnant.
No, but that's what I was going to bring
up is that part of the reason you
actually approached me about coming on
the podcast and it's a that over the
last few years you've actually been
doing a ton of experiments and actually
trying to grow the app and have been
very successful grown MRR almost 3x in
the last couple of years. So I did want
to like start digging into like now
you're a subscription app. The story a
lot of people can't relate to all the
early days of the App Store and stuff.
But I think what what a lot of people
will be able to relate to is 3x revenue
by experimenting with stuff. So I wanted
to dig into that. So what are the things
that you've done in the last couple of
years that really moved the needle on
that?
Yeah, it's interesting because we yeah,
we I mean we started using subscriptions
I think when they were introduced in
and at the time we didn't want you know,
to force subscription on our users
because they um
I feel like utilities it was one of
these things where it's like a
subscription going to fly, you know, are
people going to pay for this?
And people didn't receive subscribe I
mean yeah, you could get a lot of
backlash from
your customers, right? And so, what what
we did is basically we added a
subscription for a new service called
Genius Cloud so to back up and and your
documents in the cloud and and actually
we kept the one-time purchase for the
premium features. And so, this basically
the customer were paying for this back
up and seeking the cloud, but they were
buying storage and they were
understanding
that you buy storage, there is a
recurring fee, you know, it was more
like a
And it wasn't I mean, we didn't get any
backlash. And I think in 2020 we what we
did is that we switched we started
adding premium features to that
subscription. We renamed it from like
Genius Cloud to Genius Scan Ultra. And
we had two tiers of subscription. We we
also added Genius Scan Plus tier. So,
that was the the former like legacy
one-time purchase became a subscription.
And what we did, we grandfathered all
our existing users. So, the one who have
purchased it in 2010, they for 99 cents,
they still have it like the premium most
of the premium features maybe.
Trust me, taking something away from
somebody, even if it's 99 cents, almost
never worth it.
Yeah, exactly. And and and they can go
to the premium more premium plan if they
want to add more
Yeah, give them paths to upgrade. You
don't have to give them more stuff. I
think you give them, you know, you can
hold back features and stuff like that,
but like I think I've seen folks like
sometimes there are reasons to go back
and raise prices, but like typically
it's just the the backlash is just not
worth it. That can cost you your whole
business.
Especially if you're in a I think it's
still like a growing expanding market
where you know, you have more user
coming. You don't have a like a fixed
user base. You don't have to yeah,
nurture your existing user base, right?
And so, at that time
2020 we had like two subscription tiers.
We had Genius Scan Plus which was
I think 99 cents a month and Genius Scan
Ultra which was a
three
dollars a month.
And they like you know, equivalent
pricing for yearly. After that that we
start we didn't make any experiment at
the time. We just you know start two
tiers, one for lower end
like purchase there and
and more premium purchases. And after
last year we started experimenting. And
what we did is that we removed plus
tier. So still we grant I mean we
everyone keep using it, right? And we
kept the pre ultra tier. And that what
we noticed is that demand curve is not
elastic at all. Like people who were
like we had a 100 great purchase per day
split between plus and ultra. We still
had a 100 purchase per day, but it was
ultra.
You're very far off of like where the
main of elasticity, right? That doesn't
surprise me. Was it still 99 cents when
you
No. No, no, no. So now I mean well I
mean yeah.
The low tier was 99 cents. Yeah, I bet
that was cuz I would have guessed that
that's probably already on its own way
under priced. So you were probably
preventing a bunch of users who would
have paid more for that and happily paid
for the ultra, but they were just like
this is good enough. And so by make
yeah, it doesn't surprise me. But these
are the things you don't know that until
you try it, you know, that's going to
make a difference.
What we did is like we are now we have
the last year we had the still like the
ultra subscription with a monthly and
yearly subscription. And both were
exposed at the same level. And basically
we buried the plus
monthly subscription.
So you could still access it, but it was
you would have to go a bit further in
the paywall. Same thing we had most
people switch to the yearly I mean
everyone switched to the yearly
subscription. Ultra subscription now is
was I think was
it was 20-ish 25 maybe in 2020. And now
it's 40
I mean 40-ish.
like $4 a month, $3, $4 a month, right?
Yeah, which I would bet I don't know
what your competitors are priced at, but
I would bet that you guys are still
probably comparatively low.
I mean depends because I think most of
lots of competitors do like stuff with
weekly subscriptions, you know.
Yeah, sure, sure. Yeah, yeah. I was
going to say that even that 99 cent
price point that you guys were able to
run for a while, I think that's doable
for you because you weren't dependent on
paid acquisition. You kind of had your
own destiny and by doing that you
preserved a tremendous amount of brand
equity. You probably were you know, that
that's what endeared you with the
customers and so even though like you
maybe left $3 a month on the table on
that, you have to imagine like what you
may you probably also gained which is
like a still a position a fighting
position against Adobe.
You know, like a hundred billion dollar
company.
Yeah, and also far as you can actually
because we switched from I think it was
$9.99 one time purchase at the time. We
said we switched switch that to one
night $9.99 a year, you know, it's
already like for us it like if if some
people people stick like a few years
it's already you know, a great upgrade,
right? And so that's that's way where it
came from and I think it's fine. I mean
you have to easy to have regrets but we
can keep experimenting on that and I
think looking at the pricing increasing
it's the
part of the next experiments we want to
run with with revenue get.
Yeah, I mean if you're building new
things and you're providing more value,
like keep messing around with it until
you you know, it'll always probably be
worth it. I mean we're still looking at
our pricing like every year, every other
year, especially on like like our sold
side like there's it's more easy to
experiment there. I wanted to like kind
of jump back but like it's related all
this stuff but when did you all like
bring cuz you mentioned hiring people
like that's kind of a big jump to go
from you and your co-founder to like now
you're an employer,
right? When when and why did you make
that decision?
So in 2014 I I moved back to France and
we started working with Guillaume and I
think in in 2015 we started hiring first
employee.
And what prompted that I think that what
was that we had too much on our plate.
We were like
doing so many things and we needed a new
another iOS developer to help and we
recruited him and and that's still how
we do things now is like when we feel
like um
we feel a bit of pain, you know, we
start hiring. It doesn't mean that we
overwork, but it's just like
when during your day you are I'm still
developing and I I don't, you know, I
like for instance last year I was doing
like a product and and support and
developments uh administrative work and
I can't do all that if I want to still,
you know, do some development then I
have to offload product and support for
instance to other people and that's how
for instance we hired like a support
person 3 years ago.
Uh product manager like this year for
instance.
It's interesting there's an implicit
choice you made there that maybe you
didn't even think about, but you could
have not hired somebody and just done
less stuff. You know, but you did choose
you did choose to instead of taking the
path of like dialing back and just being
happy with what you had, you said like
no, okay, let's make an investment and
like let's take some risk and
And you say an investment we but we
yeah, it's not again it's a bit
different I think from venture funded
companies where you, you know, you make
a business plan, you say, if I raise
this much money, I will hire hire all
these many people in, you know, sales
and and developers and And that's the
plan. Never goes as planned, but
Yeah, I just stopped making plans. Like
I made two of those and they did they
were fantasy, so I just like we're just
not going to do that. We do what you do.
I do what you do. Just be like what
hurts the most and then we hire there.
It's still when you talk to other people
it generally they want I mean when you
raise money you need this plan because
they want to know how it's going to be
used, right? And so that what also
For instance that an invest I mean
that's could be the other path. We could
say, okay, we're going to invest in more
people to to grow. I mean because we
think that if we hire uh for instance
this iOS I will do this feature and then
we'll get more growth and it's not
really the reasoning it's more like a we
have so many things to do that we want
to do. It's not necessarily like they
are growth driven. It's like
just I have too much on my plate. I need
someone.
I'm slow walking you Bruno into
realizing you're a cold hearted
capitalist. I don't know if you I don't
know if if you realize what's happening,
but we don't have to call it an
investment. We can call it whatever you
want. I mean there's a reality there
that like and I think this is I mean
Miguel and I went through a very similar
transition like we went a different path
once you raise money it was like hire
people whatever but I think it wasn't as
clear to me and hopefully you've seen
this too is like good people you hire
good people they solve problems right
and you can just do more things and it's
there's like two big phase shifts in
somebody building a thing there's like
I'm building a thing that's a project
then there's the first jump which is
like okay I'm building a thing it's now
my thing it's now my main thing and then
that that second transition which we're
talking about now which is like okay
this is now a concern for other people
that I'm going to bring into this thing
and like now it's a business that's a
company and a business I think beyond
that it's actually kind of more of the
same right it's like okay like there
might be no bigger transition than those
two
and I don't know I think there's a lot
of really successful indies that are
kind of in that between those first two
decision points where you know David
you've always kind of been maybe in
between those two where you've like
worked with contract you kind of like
strung it together and arguably maybe if
like you had gotten some commitment and
like you know there would have been a
benefits to that right but it's it's
scary right it's a risk
Yeah and it well it was always a
conscious choice on my part too though I
mean I talked to VCs in like 2008
2009 and I made that conscious choice
was like I didn't want to be on that
treadmill and I didn't want the
complexity of managing people like to me
I chose the passion side of it was like
it was really fun building apps and I
knew it was not going to be fun managing
employees making payroll all those kind
of things and it was a very conscious
choice of of mine and you know looking
back I could have built a bigger
business and in some ways maybe have
been less stressed like
Yeah it depends it depends on who you
hire
I mean I it could have like flamed out
or it could have like gone even better
because I mean and you know what I
figured out over time was like my model
with contractors and everything else
came with its own like massive headaches
and problems and it was there were many
times along the journey I was like I
should have just hired somebody because
this whole contractor like working
part-time, you know, not working for
months and it had its own nice but but
yeah, that I mean there's choices all
along the way. I remember Jacob we sat
on the patio of the Airbnb at the 2019
RevenueCat offsite with five employees
or however many we we were like seven
people total at that time and I remember
having a conversation with you of like
RevenueCat could be this just amazing
little cash generating business and the
seven of us travel the world and surf
and and I remember that being like a
decision point for you is like you know,
you'd only raise like one and a half
million. They weren't like massive
expect you know, like
Hopefully Jason doesn't listen to all
these podcasts cuz I was always fully
intended on returning him his capital in
in multiples.
But there's like micro decisions all
along
And I'll tell you I mean not to not to
make this about me but like I think
those decision points kind of never
stop. Like as you're scaling a business
Brennan, you're going through those now.
It's like every year it's like okay, do
we double down or do we kind of just be
happy with what we got? Do we take more
risk, you know?
I mean it depends on I feel like it
depends on also like where you are in
life, you know, where I'm with young
kids. I don't maybe want you know, to
spend too much time working. I you know,
I when I spend nights and weekends doing
work, I was you know, 25. It's I had the
time to do that and so it's different
but even I like I think that for
instance we have 10 employees now and
that's still you know, we could be 20
but what's you have to take in also in
account that the nature of what you do
will change then. As David said you can
you would I like doing some development
but we are 10 people. I can still do
some development. If we are 20, it will
be less and less development. I will be
doing more like synchronizing people,
project management.
Yeah, people problems. I mean it's just
and it depends on who you hire in the
company culture and stuff like that but
yeah.
I mean we are very lucky that we have
very little I mean we we try to hire
like very independent like people and so
we we have very little management to do.
We have a you know low turnover. So
yeah, it really depends on who you are
higher and you have to be mindful of
that I guess when you hire.
Yeah, which but but even that itself
that's hard work. I think for a lot of
like technical people who are makers.
Ask me how I know. But
getting a team right it's very it's
technical. It's hard. It's like just
hours and then it's very emotionally
taxing too because like inevitably
you'll make mistakes along the way.
You'll have to like give people tough
news. You'll have to give you know like
just depends on what energizes you and
what you know and that's that's a
decision that you know honestly like
I'll say like when we made that first
choice to go raise money and kind of do
this versus versus stay in that first
zone. Unless you've done it before I
don't think it really you don't really
understand what that's like. You
probably have a taste of it now but I
think also it's nice that you have
control over your destiny there and you
can kind of decide at what pace do I
want to like bring this on and like like
I kind of forced to it in some degrees,
right? Like I kind of have to.
Sometimes life if you have no choice
it's a little bit easier because you
don't have to worry about it. But yeah,
you can take it every day. You can take
it day by day and depend you know when
your kids are older or you maybe you
have a little bit more time like maybe
it changes like your your mindset
changes around it, right?
And maybe there won't be any any more
documents to scan then.
Yeah, right. There you go. There you go.
That's a good point. That's a good
point. Maybe you should call those M&A
people up just in case.
Well, we've been talking about like all
the growth and uh the journey but every
journey has a bunch of fails and when we
were prepping for the podcast you wrote
down some really great fails. So I want
to make sure we got to these. So tell me
about some of the like massive screw ups
you made along the way and and how you
recovered from them.
David's a little mas- massive screw up
is a little editorializing there.
Well, I mean he shared them with me.
They were
some big ones.
There are many related to conversion
like to the paywall conversion so it's
very relevant to RevenueCat I guess.
Basically, we we were always measuring
like paywall like how many times the our
paywall is displayed from
what feature in the app. In the app when
you you are trying to use some premium
features, that's where we're going to
show you the the paywall and it could be
you try to export to Dropbox, that's
paywall or you can you would try to use
a text recognition OCR, that's also
behind the paywall. And so in
a few years ago we did a
an update where we um
redid the UX of uh the a screen where
you see all the scanned documents.
That was a really nice screen. I mean,
much better, much nicer and after a
while I'm looking at analytics and I'm
seeing that our paywall uh is actually
displayed much less than than it used to
be. So I'm trying to investigate and I
don't know it's linked to this
refactoring of the screen. So I figured
out that it was linked to this uh
caused by this uh change
of the screen and and the reason why was
that we had one of the reason people
were opening the paywall for was because
they tried to access the OCR of the
document and on the former screen we had
a button on the
on the scan document that you would tap
and it would show the you know OCR text
and after this refactoring we had moved
this button in a
basically in a drawer
and and was not directly visible and the
effect on the paywall displays was like
maybe like 10 20% I don't know the exact
number in in uh
in my mind but
Which is a direct 10 20% of your sales,
right? Like it's
It was actually I think you're also a
high intent purchase.
So it was maybe one even higher more
than the relative presentation.
So maybe it was like a you know 10% less
displays and 20% less. And that's
something I noticed like after like
months after.
So for months your revenue had gone down
but you couldn't quite figure like you
thought maybe like the market was
shifting you
Exactly. That's where it's hard. You
have so many factors you have
you have seasonality, you know, it's
Christmas, people are buying more
phones, so you have get a big jump in
maybe in purchases, but then in March, I
think it happened in March, like maybe
you know the Christmas time is over and
people stop purchasing. Maybe it was
that. It could be yeah, market shifting,
maybe it could be I ASO that has changed
and we are a small team, we don't have
like a you know, data person like
looking at this data every day, which I
guess if we had maybe
No, no, but but we are looking into into
having I mean we are looking at the
matrix more regularly and we try to like
I mean you're the data person, right? I
think it's just about making it easy for
you to look at that stuff every day.
Yeah, exactly.
That's so crazy. Like one of the primary
upsell features, you accidentally like
broke essentially. Did you put it back
in that same place and then like like
everything like came back?
Exactly, we clearly saw saw the result.
Yeah, it was and and and there was
another instance of that fairly recent.
We had
so in the free version of Genius Scan we
have an ad banner. It's not a third
party ad banner because we removed that
a while ago, but it's it's like an ad
banner but it promotes the premium
version. What happens is that so this ad
banner
ad banner has some text like I think it
was Genius Scan Ultra and some text and
if you tap on it you show the paywall
and it's directly on the main screen of
Genius Scan, so it's fairly visible and
it's one of the leading entries to the
paywall. And this banner is served by a
by a server, so we can change the text
and and remove it. And what happened is
that the server went down. One of the
reasons that we tracked taps on the
banner and the
integer
on the database overflow.
It was not a big int, it was just an
int, so
I have a friend of mine whose like
favorite phrase is like when we're
setting up apps, like stuff he's always
he's like always use big int. You got to
be optimistic, you know?
And so so the app was nicely designed
because we had in the app hard coded we
had a fallback ad. So if the remote ad
banner wasn't displayed we would show
the fallback ad. And what happened is
actually I noticed in the paywall
metrics that our purchase had increased
for a while. I guess I should have told
the story the other way but I noticed
our purchases had increased. I started
investigating why and that's
when I linked that back to the ad banner
that wasn't displayed from the remote
server anymore and the fallback banner
that was displayed most of the time.
So it was like a
accidental AB test.
It's accidental AB test, yeah. And so
the fallback banner was converting twice
twice as much as as existing better. We
restored the I mean we fixed the remote
server and what we still have two
banners one with a
old text and one with the same text as
the fallback banner and this confirmed
that the text of the fallback banner was
I mean the text and the icon was
slightly different but I mean you saw
the the images in the in the document
and it's I don't understand how
how was such small changes can I mean
It's the problem is that you're not
you're not a thousand people, right?
You're one person, right? And you just
have to test these things otherwise it's
really difficult to reason about.
Right but but even just yeah the effect
of changing the text test is like
I guess it blows my mind that
just changing the text changing an icon
has such an effect on conversion. I I
really don't I mean it's
Yeah, I've I've long learned that even
if you're a person with really good
product sense or you think you have
really good product sense there's a
limit. There's just a limit. You just
can't know like what there's some
obvious rules that almost always
followed but like fewer steps is almost
always better. Showing the paywall more
is almost always better. But besides
that like I don't think there's a way to
deterministically understand like what's
going on and it's just it's much faster
to just do something. It's It's
interesting that what you did on
accident there is this kind of concept I
try to run in management and just life
is like injecting variance. Like just
even if you're unintentional a little
bit, like change stuff and you'll learn
things.
Well, you see it's like
I'm thinking of Netflix. I think they
had the I don't know how it was called
but they had these crazy monkeys. It was
like a series that would kill a random
server.
Monkey. Chaos Monkey, right? Yeah, they
would break random services.
Yeah, to make sure that they had these
variants in their back end that make
sure that if if it actually happens for
a bad reason someday then they they're
ready for it, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I I think it's it's
super important and like I think
sometimes it can be unsettling in my
leadership style. David can probably
attest to this but like I will just be
like, "Yeah, I don't know what we're
going to do but we're just going to do
something different. We're just going to
break it and see what how it how we
reassemble it and not try to
analytically solve every little thing we
do and justify every little thing we do
cuz like probably we'll learn more just
by trying it and then we will by we'll
certainly learn more by trying something
semi-thought through than not doing
anything and just thinking about it for
a very long time, right?
And also you you could be completely
data-driven but it's it's boring, you
know?
Where's the fun in that?
I want to use my intuition. I mean I'm
ready to you can prove me I'm wrong
after after I use it but at least let me
use it, right? We are humans building
companies not Otherwise, you know, you
just replace the company by AI just like
Yeah, the the human element. Maybe
that'll go away once the computers are
so good they can replicate the human
element but
But the question again the question what
are you doing a company for, you know?
Are you because you're having fun or
because you want to make money? And I
think both of us is we want I mean it's
like you gather a group of people to
have
fun building something, you know? So
Yeah, but it's like if you're just
executing sort of mechanically a
playbook on strategy, there's nothing
differentiated there. You're not going
to beat the market if it's some, you
know, just being like we're going to AB
test and only do that and not use
intuition. Like you don't have an
advantage. You have nothing unique about
that cuz it's just like unless you maybe
like maybe Duolingo is a good example.
They just were really really good at AB
testing better than anybody in the
world.
Yeah, but even that they have to add the
creativity, you know, to create like um
And talking to the product manager, we
had him on the on the podcast, a product
manager at Duolingo, one of the things
he said was that that the the founders,
I think, end up reviewing a lot of the
like winning and will sometimes decide
to not pick a winning AB test.
Yeah, I mean, there was a period, I
think, at Facebook where they were just
only following AB test stuff and like
you kind of saw the product get a little
wonky and then I think they they pulled
This was a big meme in in the 2010s,
right?
My favorite quote on this was Thomas
Petit, who of course will make it crass,
but if you AB test enough, you're going
to end up with a porn app or a gambling
And I mean, like if you AB test without
intuition, without thinking about
differentiation, without thinking about
like being customer-centric,
which I want to talk more about like how
you think about being customer-centric,
but like if you AB test without a
framework above and like Jacob, like you
were talking about like you tear things
down and rebuild and everything like
that, but we have such a clear mission
here RevenueCat to help developers make
more money that you can apply that
framework against these decisions we're
making to like make progress in the
direction of serving the goal.
It's not like by blowing up the thing,
we don't know where we're trying to get
eventually, still, right?
if I do anything for AB test, you you
It's hard to AB test on the very long
time. I think like Shopify does that.
You see keep like experiments running
for like a years, but but most people,
you know, you do an AB test for a month
and then you say, "Okay, that's better."
But then, as you said, like you're going
to end up with a That's a actually a
interesting point like we
at Faraway Engineers in the free version
of Genius Scan, we monetize it with
advertisement.
And we noticed that the the best
performing advertisement, they were like
for, you know, casino games or whatever
is legal to be displayed, but the
ugliest, you know, worst quality
advertisement are the the one performing
better, at least at the time. And after
a while, we were like we we I mean, we
we didn't want advertisement in the app.
It was ruining the quality. It was like
ugly. We don't like, you know, making
people buy buy they don't need.
Like, it's just like So, we decided to
remove it. But if we had AB tested, like
I mean, what's better? Like, clearly it
was better to keep the advertisement.
But long term, I'm not sure, you know?
The people who still like use the free
app have a very good experience. They
are the one recommending to their, you
know, family. Maybe they recommend their
kids use it because there is no
advertisement and it's, you know, safe
to use or whatever. That's the value you
can measure, but you you know, you you
can make a choice as a as a leader of
the company to to go that direction.
This might blow people's minds, but
we've never run an AB test. I mean,
we've run very very small like marketing
page AB tests here, but like we've I've
never really run like simultaneous tests
on RevenueCat, the product, because like
it's it's harder with what we do. But
then also, kind of for that reason, I
just look at the data. Like, kind of
what you were saying. I think there was
a point here I wanted to like express to
our listeners, which is like this idea
of like you don't need a data person,
and you don't need like a whole data
analyst shop. Just have like
somewhere where you can see your five or
10 most important things and look at
them every single day. I get an email.
The first thing I do every morning, I my
alarm goes off, I grab my phone, I go
and I look at my I look at my like
founder update email, and it tells me
all the kind of like the the paywall
views. Like, that which should be
probably something you're looking at
every single day. Like, what is the
total number of paywall impressions?
Even that, you know, you have like
you know, it's Christmas, your paywall
view will drop. Or like for us, we are
in Europe and like it's Monday,
September 1st. I was like, "Where are
all the paywall views done?" Okay, it's
a Memorial Day or whatever. It's like
And and so, you have still to take that
into account. And like, yeah, I feel
like you can you can do that. And I do,
you know, look at the metrics very
often, but you also have to, I think,
look once a month at like more, you
know,
Yeah, yeah, you need you need to look at
it at multiple scales, right? You need
to look at it at the daily scale, the
monthly scale.
You want to take the pulse, and you also
want, you know, to have the higher level
uh
higher overview of the metrics, yeah.
This conversation has brought up like 20
RevenueCat features we need to start
working on, Jacob. Better AB testing
tools, cuz I never I never did a paywall
or pricing test until RevenueCat
released experiments, and I was able to
do it easily. So, now we need we need AB
testing tooling to make this easier.
impressions. We need to be tracking
paywall impressions. Like, we have it
with our paywalls, but like building
that in natively and making it in the
day in the charts and stuff. Like,
that's
What you were just saying, what I love
about your charts, cuz you're such a
data nerd, is that you have rolling
averages over different time frames.
That that needs to be on our dashboard,
too.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You see that So, I
always chart the I'm just going to get
into my chart my chart theories here,
but like I always chart the like daily
value, and then the 30-day rolling
average, and the 90-day rolling average.
And like basically, like if I want to
know if a metric is healthy and
increasing, if the 30-day is above the
90-day, like we're good. If 30-day is
below the 90-day, we're not we're like
trending in the wrong direction. But
then also like the individual days I
think are useful for what you said, like
oh, did something happen yesterday,
right? Was there a big pop somewhere?
So.
Yeah, charts charts 3.0. There you go.
Why are you building this great stuff
for yourself and not delivering it to
your customers, Jacob? I want that.
Cuz I got I got all kinds of stuff to
do. I got I got What did What did you
say people alignment to do, Brynner? Or
like something like that?
And speaking of customer-centric,
there's something we were talking about
before we hit record. I wish we had to
hit record when we were just chatting.
And there's so many good conversations
before we hit record on the podcast. So,
we can try to recreate the magic, but we
were talking about AI chatbots and like
pretending to do customer service with
AI, and you brought up like how
un-customer-centric that is. So, I
wanted to like keep pulling on that
thread of just how customer-centric
you think in building Genius Scan.
And one of the main thing we, you know,
we don't have values on our website, but
but one thing is that we try to build
the app we want to use, right? And when
part of that is that when you you have a
problem, you you contact support and you
get the answer you need. And you know,
it could be I mean, you can go on the
knowledge base and find the answer, but
you can also want to talk to someone and
they give you an appropriate response. I
mean, we are so used on websites and and
apps to you you there's a chatbot that's
supposed to help you and then what you
just keep typing is like talk to a
human. Talk to a human. Yeah, I want to
talk to someone. I want to talk to
someone and and and they will never like
let you until you you go deep in that
decision tree and and and bail out
because they, you know, don't know how
to answer. And I feel like it's such a
bad experience, you know, it's it's if
you have a problem in the app, you're in
a
maybe the situation of distress, you
know, you need to talk to a to a person.
It's uh
I think it's a need as a human in that
case and and we want to offer that. So,
we really do that. I mean, we don't do
like phone support because it's not
scalable as an app, but we do support
for everyone. We've been doing that for
like past 15 years. We just do email
support. For a very long time, it's me
and my co-founder, we were replying to
support ourselves. And I think that's
super helpful because that's you get
such a good pulse of of the problems and
you even get like in your you know, we
for a very long time, we didn't have any
and still now and we don't have a
complete backlog of, you know, feature
requests. We just we let that
you know, sink. Every time we hear about
a feature you hear it once, twice, 10
times. You you
you know, you know, you know in yourself
that that's a need, right? That's been a
super helpful and we are still like
today, we are still like reviewing
support as founders of the company. We
still do like every day. I go and I help
for like more technical issues or more
specific problems.
Well, one doing tickets is painful, kind
of. You know, you got to write these
responses. It's kind of a pain. So, I
think like in some ways it creates this
interesting mirror empathy situation
where like the customer's in pain
reaching out to you. You're doing
tickets, which kind of sucks. So, that's
pain as well. And now you're both in
pain, especially if it's a product
problem that you created. Now now you
like physically feel their pain, and I
think that motivates you to like do
something about it. I'm actually bad
about that. You I mean, when I could, I
did all of the tickets, right? And then
it became you know, it becomes too big,
and then you you get it off in systems
and whatever. But just having that
moment to like really empathize, like
take take that break, that beat. Cuz you
can look at it in aggregates, right? You
can you know, "Oh, 47% of users had this
problem." Blah blah blah. That doesn't
hit as well as like seeing a a single
individual person struggling with that
problem.
Yeah, that's the only way you have to
connect with people. You know, you can
do like user research in person, you
bring people and they you can do that
again.
Do you talk to users? Like do you call
them ever?
No, we I mean, sometimes people ask us
to call them, but it's I mean, most of
our users are US-based. We are based in
France, so it's you know, time
difference makes it complicated. It
happens that we did it, but
you know, mostly it's email.
And I think it would help with empathy
to have people on the phone.
I was just listening to a podcast with
David Lieb on the YC podcast. He he
talked about doing customer interviews,
and one day he just was like exported
the top 100 most active users, sent all
100 of them an email, and talked to them
like wanted to like 15 minutes with all
of them. And I was just like, "Oh, like
that would be a fantastic" I think every
app developer could do that. It's just
try that. Like grab your 100 most active
users, and talk to all just make a make
a list and just talk to all of them. Now
as a support case, but just like
phrases terrifying, right? They might
not talk to you, but I guarantee you
learn something super interesting on
that call, so.
Yeah, and it gets back to it's you know,
so many things we've touched on in the
last hour is like that focus on
customers just helps you make better
decisions, and it's ultimately
differentiating. You know, those scammy
scanner apps that aren't talking to
users, that are only running AB tests,
that are thin on margins. Like, they're
not differentiated in part because they
don't care. They don't talk to their
users. They don't build what they want.
Yeah, I think is they don't see they
don't see their users are as a people
maybe, you know, they just see it as a
source of money. And And And there are
things like I mean, with dark patterns
that means they would do like a friends
I don't know if it's still considered as
a dark pattern, but you know, they're
showing on we don't have an onboarding
for instance. We don't show the paywall
on onboarding. And if you talk, you
know, to a
paywall specialist, they will tell you
that the biggest mistake
Bruno, what if I told you I could triple
your revenue in 2025?
You know, I think there is probably a
right way of doing it. And I'm not
saying you shouldn't do that, but but
when you get the paywall on onboarding
and where you know, there is a little
cross at the top right that fades in
slowly so that you think that the only
option is to pay.
For you all, so many utility apps do
that where they like they're not going
to let you go any further or they make
it very hard to get the freemium
experience. Like, everything I hear
about about your product and your brand
and like the way you run the company, I
think that's actually your
differentiated value. It's like
Yeah, and and also I think it's a
benefit in the long term because like
customers of these apps, I'm pretty sure
that I mean, they churn pretty high
because they don't have a if they don't
have a good experience. Whereas our
users, we have like a free free users
and and some of them convert in the long
term. And they're also like a benefit
because they recommend like the app to
their we we know that for a fact that
they do that to friends, family, and and
that's I I I think that's the best like
the best recommendation you can have is
like from your a fellow, you know, if
someone tells you, "Oh, I have this app
is super nice." They show it to you in a
in a bar or whatever and it's like,
"Okay, I'm going to download it."
I mean, one of the biggest indications
of product market fit or successful
product is just how much what percentage
of your growth is word of mouth. That's
like a very hard to fake. One trick for
you and our listeners, just ask the ask
customers. Maybe it's hard without an
onboarding, but you could put for 5% of
users, pop them a survey. It's It's "How
did you hear about us?" Three big
buttons and make it really easy to
cancel. It'll be a little bit of a
sacrifice of customer experience, but
like you'll get enough data to like
notionally I didn't think that would be
all that helpful. We put it in
RevenueCat, and like I I look at that
every day. I look at what everybody
answered every day, because it's it's
We also have free form, which is really
fascinating. Like we learn about like
ways people are That's how I learned
that ChatGPT was telling people to use
RevenueCat and when they asked how to
win at purchases, people like all of a
sudden I saw Claude, ChatGPT, like all
the LLMs. I was like, Oh, I wouldn't
have even thought to ask about that.
It's really fascinating. So, open-ended
surveys on that can be directional,
right? You're just learning
directionally.
Yeah, for us that open-ended surveys
they end up with my email doesn't work.
Sure. You get that, too?
We have
Let me say it's interesting because it's
like we have like a very
I mean, we have people, you know, in
small businesses, but we have really
like everyone like from students,
stay-at-home moms.
Well, it's like it's like it's such a
wide variety of customers and it's it's
it's so nice. I mean, it's uh
to have that.
Well, I I think it's a great place to
wrap up. You've built something truly
great with this business. Like something
you can be proud of, and also something
that has a ton of opportunity to
continue growing. And and like Jacob was
saying, if you were very aggressive with
your paywall, you probably could triple
revenue in 2025. But that may not be the
right move, but you might find something
that works with your brand the way you
want that freemium experience to happen
with the way you want your product to
feel to your customers. And you may
still double revenue. The crazy little
like accidental AB test was honestly so
inspiring for me, because there are just
so many little way in a product that's
working, in a product that has some
level of product market fit, there are
probably thousands of different ways to
continue growing that product, even from
just changing the text in the default
ad.
You just got to do stuff, yeah.
Yeah, it's inspiring, but it's still
still scary, I find.
Because it can go up or it can go down.
And you know, you might add a feature
that kind of hides a bit another one.
And yeah, it's but it's that's what what
makes it interesting, right? It's like
there's some risk in it. And
Yeah, it makes the game fun, right?
Exactly.
Well, anything you wanted to share
before wrapping up? We're going to share
a link to your Twitter and Blue Sky
profiles. I guess everybody should just
go download uh Genius Scan, huh?
Yeah, just give it give it a try and and
and let us know if you if you like it or
dislike it. We would love to know.
Honestly, it's like a
We we like
feedback from customers. It's a
Well, it's been so much fun chatting
with you today. Thanks for joining us.
Thanks for inviting me. It was very fun
nice um talking with you. Take
Finally. I'll see you I'll talk again in
7 years.
Thanks so much for listening.
If you have a minute, please leave a
review in your favorite podcast player.
You can also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.